Guide to the Hal Goodtree papers, 1987-2004 and undated RL.11614
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hal Goodtree papers
1987-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Goodtree, Hal
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11614
7.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive and producer for Benton & Bowles (DMB&B) and other agencies, primarily based in New York; later self-employed as a commercial producer and documdentary filmmaker based in Cary, N.C. Collection includes correspondence and television commercial production notes (including bids, casting notes, shooting sequences, storyboards, staffing lists and expense reports) and audiovisual materials in multiple formats (videocassettes, digital video, video tape reels). Companies represented include Audi, Cheerwine, HBO, Health-tex (VF Corp.), Leukemia & Lymphoma Society, New York Times, NFL, Road Runner (Time Warner) and the U.S. Postal Service. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Production Records; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Producer, Benton & Bowles 1981-1994; founder of Goodtree & Company, an umbrella organization based in Cary, N.C.; Awards: 1995 Emmy for best sports promotional announcement (New York Mets, Sportschannel); 2002 Cannes advertising Golden Lion for an anti-smoking PSA for Alabama Tobacco Free Families; Producer of documentaries "American Tobacco and the Durham Renaissance" (2014) and "Soldiers of Truth--The History of Shaw University" (2017)
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Hal Goodtree papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles archives
J. Walter Thompson Company. Anthony J. Viola papers
Joy Golden papers
Leonard Sirowitz papers
Richard W. Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence and television commercial production notes (including bids, casting notes, shooting sequences, storyboards, staffing lists and expense reports) and audiovisual materials in multiple formats (videocassettes, digital video, video tape reels). Companies represented include Audi, Cheerwine, HBO, Health-tex (VF Corp.), Leukemia & Lymphoma Society, New York Times, NFL, Road Runner (Time Warner) and the U.S. Postal Service. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; Television advertising; Television commercials; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Home Box Office (Firm); New York Times; National Football League; Time, Inc.; United States Postal Service
- Production Records, 1998-2004 and undated; 1
  - 1998 (Box 1)
  - 2001-2002, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 2003 (Box 1)
  - 2003 (Box 1)
  - 2002, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 2004 (Box 1)
  - 1998, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 2001, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - 2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 2004 (Box 2)
  - 2004 and undated (Box 2)
  - 2000 (Box 2)
  - 2004, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 2000 (Box 3)
  - 2001, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 1999, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - 2003 (Box 3)
  - 2001 (Box 3)
  - 2000 (Box 3)
  - 2001 (Box 3)
  - 1999 (Box 3)
  - 1998, 3 folders (Box 3)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1987-2002 and undated; 2
  - 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-001)
  - 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-002)
  - 1990 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-003)
  - 1993 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-004)
  - 1991 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-007)
  - 1992 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-005)
  - 1990 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-006)
  - 1990 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-008)
  - 1990 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-009)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-010)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-011)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-012)
  - 1989 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-013)
  - 1990 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-014)
  - 2000 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-015)
  - 2000 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-016)
  - 2000 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-017)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-018)
  - 1993 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-019)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-020)
  - 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-021)
  - 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-022)
  - 2002 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-023)
  - 2002 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-024)
  - 1998 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-025)
  - 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-026)
  - undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-027)
  - 1998 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11614-VHS-028)
  - 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-001)
  - undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-002)
  - 1987 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-003)
  - 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-004)
  - 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-005)
  - 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-Umatic-006)
  - 1995 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-D2-001)
  - 1997 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11614-D2-002)
  - 1989 (Box AV2, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-001)
  - 1994 (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-002)
  - undated (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-003)
  - 1990 (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-004)
  - 1993 (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-005)
  - 1994 (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-006)
  - 1993 (Box AV3, Video-reel RL11614-Vid1-007)